<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Alexander Dawson</title>
	<id>https://alexanderdawson.com/</id>
	<subtitle>All the latest news and releases from Alexander Dawson</subtitle>
	<updated>2023-03-03</updated>
	<link rel="self" href="https://domain.com/atom.xml" type="application/atom+xml" />
	<entry>
		<title>Medica11y Launched!</title>
		<updated>2023-07-01</updated>
		<id>https://medica11y.com/</id>
		<content type="html"><p>Medica11y is a Personal Health Record app with a difference, it focuses on your privacy! Built using open web standards, never transmitting or storing any data, and you can store, share, or edit the record however you choose (including within secure password managers); it's a free, honest, utility for anyone looking to manage complex conditions.</p></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Semantic Web Hook Launched!</title>
		<updated>2023-05-01</updated>
		<id>https://swhook.com/</id>
		<content type="html"><p>SWHook is a simple, dependency free Microdata JavaScript framework. It turns semantic information embedded within the page into useful functionality for end-users. Once added to a website, this automated library will sniff markup on the fly for compatible microdata and transform it into a useful browser-based format for your visitors. This library adds no bloat, it just enhances what's there on the Semantic Web!</p></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Syntaxonomy Launched!</title>
		<updated>2023-04-02</updated>
		<id>https://syntaxonomy.com/</id>
		<content type="html"><p>The word Syntaxonomy is to bridge a collection (taxonomy) of languages (syntax). In this instance this website is the cumulative assortment of useful links and articles I have found over 20+ years of Web Development. Consider these the must-reads, the insightful philosophies, and the fundamentals. All have been stacked into categories based upon the order you might learn about them through your career.</p></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Printed Launched!</title>
		<updated>2023-03-03</updated>
		<id>https://printedcss.com/</id>
		<content type="html"><p>Print-friendly stylesheets have been around for almost as long as CSS. The idea of making your website look as good on paper as they do on the Web isn't a new idea. It isn't a new idea either to target a printer to ensure your website uses the least amount of paper and ink as possible (removing stuff that isn't required). My new CSS library takes the collective wisdom of previous libraries, extends upon them and provides useful semantic hooks and classes (plus additional new features), to make your pages as eco-friendly as possible.</p></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Website Sustainability Launched!</title>
		<updated>2023-02-01</updated>
		<id>https://websitesustainability.com/</id>
		<content type="html"><p>It's taken me many months of work, but I've finally completed a massive research project examining the carbon impact of W3C web standards like HTML and CSS. This is the first project of its type to go into such depth providing a benchmark for the emissions of a website or app. Hopefully the data will prove useful in web performance and reducing page bloat. Additionally (by request of the W3C Sustainability WG) I've produced a map of variables which showcases carbon traps throughout the websites journey from development to usage.</p></content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>New Look Website (Finally) Launched!</title>
		<updated>2023-01-28</updated>
		<id>https://alexanderdawson.com/</id>
		<content type="html"><p>After many years of being too busy with client work, then a (very) long stint of ill health, I've finally got my website redesigned. After such a long absense it really does make sense to relaunch from scratch, so I've centered my work around a fun personal site from a domain I managed to snag (which actually includes my name). As I'll be launching several side projects in the coming months, this site will be where they'll appear. My business site will focus purely on my availability for solo work. Enjoy!</p></content>
	</entry>
</feed>